Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adapted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
Perturbed by the thoughts on my mind
no matter how hard I try to sever my love.
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
All of you, take a look at Nian Gengyao's memorandum.
Niang Gengyao hopes the brotherhood between Your Majesty and Yunsi and Yuntang will be considered.
That's just the meaning on the surface.
You need to understand what
Nian Gengyao wants beneath it.
This man is trying to determine my position.
In asking Your Majesty to take brotherhood into consideration,
Nian Gengyao is actually using this to
excuse himself from Your Majesty's punishment.
He's clever, that's for sure.
If I can pardon the crimes of treason
committed by Yunsi and Yuntang,
that means I can pardon him as well
whatever crimes he commits.
General Longkodo said something similar to
Nian Gengyao's memorandum the other day.
Nian Gengyao and Longkodo
have been like my arms and shoulders.
Even they were fooled by Yunsi,
and think I've been too harsh on him.
It's a disappointing realization.
Yunsi and Yuntang were quite close to State Prince Dun
before being deprived of their noble titles.
That's why State Prince Dun expressed
the most resentment against
Your Majesty's punishments on Yunsi and Yuntang.
Now Nian Gengyao foolishly has the same thoughts.
And with military power in his hands,
I'm afraid if he is taken advantage of by State Prince Dun,
it will be disastrous.
What you have said is probably already true.
Nian Gengyao and State Prince Dun began colluding more than just a short time ago.
All of you thought that Nian Gengyao
was only avaricious and cruel.
But he is no different from those who are rebellious.
Your Majesty, we must first put an end to their relationship.
To get rid of Nian Gengyao,
State Prince Dun must be eliminated first.
Lately,
the harem has been in turmoil, plagued by jealousy.
First I'll take care of affairs in the harem
and address the state affairs afterwards.
Mr. Zhen, what His Majesty said today seems a bit odd.
I hope you can enlighten me.
You flatter me, Mr. Gūwalgiya.
Let's get to the point.
I've only been summoned to His Majesty's study twice.
So I'm not sure what His Majesty's intentions are.
Concubine Sourire is in high favor with His Maesty.
Her Highness must have informed you of some details.
His Majesty...
Oh, go ahead.
Today, His Majesty spoke of Nian Gengyao
and Longkodo in the same manner.
Could His Majesty want to get rid of
more than just Nian Gengyao?
His Majesty has a profound perspective.
It is not something we can speculate on.
For those who devote their service to His Majesty,
they will surely be well advised by His Majesty.
There's one more thing.
His Majesty is not someone who indulges in the harem.
But His Majesty said he'll deal with
the harem before the state affairs.
That is ...
It's probably because of the new Companion.
In order to soothe the jealousy in the harem,
His Majesty will have to put in some thought.
Everyone is here tonight.
This is to Your Majesties.
Wishing Your Majesties good health and long-lasting fortune.
Peace and grace to Your Majesty.
Alcohol can damage your health.
I carefully chose these grapes.
Please try some, Your Majesty
They're pleasant.
Song Zhi, are you sure you hand-picked
those grapes with care?
They weren't highly praised by His Majesty.
Perhaps you need to more carefully observe
His Majesty's preferences.
I thank Your Highness for the advice.
I've only served His Majesty since last month
and still have much to learn.
Your Highness's advice is always appreciated.
But even though I'm not as observant as Your Highness,
I am still very attentive to everything
regarding His Majesty.
Day and night, my thoughts are all about His Majesty.
I hope Your Majesty understands.
I do.
No one will dare speak of you like this in my presence.
Your Majesty has always adored Concubine Sourire
and rarely speaks up for someone else.
Looks like Your Majesty is truly fond of Song Zhi.
What you said was correct, Song Zhi.
Didn't we all have to learn about
His Majesty's preferences bit by bit?
You can't figure it out by just
having passion for His Majesty.
However, it's already July, so
you need to put in more effort.
His Majesty returns to the Palace in early August.
And on the Mid-Autumn Festival
the triennial Concubine selection will be held.
Once the new concubines arrive in plenty,
you'll have so much to worry about.
I can't possibly be as concerned as Your Highness.
Being older and in high favor of His Majesty,
Your Highness will certainly be capable of
skillfully disciplining the newcomers.
I have often heard that
"An industrious maid doesn't age."
You're not only hardworking,
but also good at speculating on your superiors.
It's no wonder Consort Fleur favored you so much
that she offered you to His Majesty.
I would never be able to provide such.
Concubine Sourire is being impertinent.
Is Your Majesty going to just sit and watch?
What is your thought on this?
A war of words is inevitable with so many women.
Everyone is in a good mood today and
has had more wine than usual.
They don't have any ill intentions.
I will speak to them after the banquet.
So this is how you have been managing the harem for me?
No wonder
the harem is constantly in turmoil!
May peace be restored in Your Majesty.
It is all my fault.
Do you know why you are at fault?
If you can't even quell a quarrel in the harem,
what are you capable of as the Empress?
I recognize my offense.
May Your Majesty's anger be calmed.
Concubine Sourire.
Your Majesty.
Leave, now.
What does Your Majesty mean?
His Majesty always makes just decisions
and would never be partial.
Concubine Sourire
breached propriety before me
and spoke indecorously.
Tomorrow,
she will be sent to Penglai Island
for self-reflection.
Forbidden to leave without my edict.
Your Majesty, Penglai Island is
located in the middle of the back lake.
It is only accessible by boat with no roads leading to it.
It is remote and has long been uninhabited.
I hope Your Majesty will forgive Concubine Sourire
as this is only her first offense.
I've served Your Majesty for three years.
Although I was discourteous,
I hope Your Majesty will take my
past service into consideration
and forgive me just this once.
I won't dare do it again.
You were speaking so arrogantly just now to Song Zhi.
If you can express such jealousy in my presence,
then how much more maliciously
do you treat her behind my back?
I did not mean it.
You've treated Song Zhi disdainfully
just because
I have been fond of her recently.
You also made many insolent remarks.
How can I tolerate such behavior?
I did not.
His Majesty has already announced his decree.
How dare you try to refute it.
I have always been outspoken.
It was not my intention to slander her.
Your Majesty, please give Concubine Sourire a
lighter punishment as it's her first offense.
Penglai Island is far too remote.
His Majesty has already announced his decree.
How dare you try to refute it?
Penglai Island is spacious.
Would you like to accompany her, Consort Estime?
Companion Zhi must be feeling aggrieved.
I will comfort her.
Su Peisheng
Yes.
Please rise, Your Highness.
I will arrange for Your Highness's
stay at Penglai Island.
Take care, Concubine Sourire.
I shall take my leave now.
Though incompetent,
I will take good care of His Majesty
in place of Your Highness.
May Your Highness have a safe trip.
- Peace and grace to Your Majesty.
- Rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
Your Majesty summoned me urgently.
I await your orders.
Something is strange about what happened tonight.
I can't put my mind at peace.
I agree with Your Majesty.
No matter how much His Majesty favors Song Zhi,
he would not get angry at Concubine Sourire.
Concubine Sourire's father has
repeatedly denounced Nian Gengyao.
Defending Song Zhi means
His Majesty is defending Consort Fleur.
Could it be that His Majesty has had a change of heart?
And now wants to maintain Nian Gengyao?
If that's the case,
then Concubine Sourire will no longer
be capable of turning the tides.
If Concubine Sourire falls out of favor,
Zhen Yuandao will also lose support.
And no one else can contend against Nian Gengyao.
I can't just watch and allow this to happen.
What does Your Majesty intend to do?
Although Nian Gengyao has been continually denounced
and His Majesty has condemned him a few times,
there has never been any actual punishment.
With Consort Fleur flourishing in the palace ...
Rather than having you be her next target,
I think it's best for you to
be there with Concubine Sourire.
It will give us time to see what unfolds.
What do you think?
But what if she is never allowed to return?
Won't that mean I'll have to stay there with her forever?
Don't worry about that.
Even if you desired
"Taoist immortality on Penglai Mountain"
I'd still bring you back to the palace.
All in all, I think it's best for you to
be there with Concubine Sourire.
Yes, Your Majesty.
I will join Concubine Sourire.
Sourire!
Are you here to send me off?
I have informed His Majesty.
I'll be going to Penglai Island with you.
What are you talking about?
I will live with you on Penglai Island.
His Majesty has granted me his consent.
So I'm not here to send you off.
Nonsense.
Do you really think you can achieve immortality
by living on Penglai Island?
If you accompany me there,
I'm afraid it will ruin your future in the palace.
There's no need to endure hardship with me.
Sourire,
I'm well aware that ever since I gained favor,
I have displeased many of the concubines.
Only you treated me with kindness
and it is "heavy as a mountain."
Once you leave,
I will have to suffer through all their disdainful eye-rolling.
I would rather accompany you
so we can look after each other there.
I congratulate Your Highness
for getting rid of a potent threat.
She has only been sent to Penglai Island.
which also sends a warning to Zhen Yuandao.
Your Highness has Song Zhi.
There's nothing to worry about.
Just drive another wedge between Concubine Sourire
and His Majesty when it's time.
And that should be enough.
That is not important now.
What's important is His Majesty has
condemned Concubine Sourire,
which also sends a warning to Zhen Yuandao.
My brother can now relax his vigilance.
Not to mention, Lady An is now gone as well.
This has clamped down on the Empress's power.
An Lingrong has no family background to rely on.
She can sing until she loses her voice, but she
is still nothing more than an entertainer.
She was fortunate enough to gain even
a moment of His Majesty's favor.
Does she think she will be so fortunate
for the rest of her life?
Speaking of which,
this outcome is all thanks to
Your Highness's well-executed plan,
and also, Companion Zhi being in favor.
Otherwise our efforts would
have been in vain.
It's true Companion Zhi is in His Majesty's good graces.
Now if she can be promoted to Attendant,
that would be even better.
And if she was to have a child,
she would even be on equal footing with me.
You're flattering me, Lady Cao.
I will forever be Your Highness's servant
regardless of my own status.
I'll remember until the day I die.
I'm glad you know your place.
Depart.
There is only one way in or out of Penglai Island.
With the boats taken away, there’s
no way to leave or enter.
I’m thankful to His Majesty for assigning
me to such a peaceful place.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
It can’t be compared to Verdant Reading Hall.
But fortunately, it’s neither desolate nor neglected.
I thought Penglai Island had become uninhabitable,
but it seems to be clean and orderly.
Even though His Majesty has chosen to heed the
words of Consort Fleur, he’s not mistreating you.
Mr. Su, I know it’s because of your efforts that
this place is so tidy and neat.
I extend my thanks to you, sir.
Your Highness has always been generous to me.
Today is but a small token of my gratitude
during this difficult time.
I’m looking forward to the day when
I can serve Your Highness again.
See, Sourire, your kindness to others is
coming back to you today.
Even I benefit from your kindness.
It’s nothing.
I have to leave soon, Your Highness.
I will have household supplies sent here.
It will be dark soon.
You should get settled, My Ladies.
Thank you, sir.
Sourire, don’t feel too discouraged.
For some reason, I feel that His Majesty
still cares about you in his heart.
He is only being deceived for now.
His Majesty may send for you again someday.
I am fine.
It’s just unfair for you to be suffering with me.
How come only Coua is here with you?
Where is Daisy? Is one servant enough?
Coua has been with me the longest.
I am used to being served by her.
You granted Daisy to me.
I couldn’t bear to have her go through this with me.
She’s back at Leisured Moon Chamber,
keeping an eye on things.
Don’t worry, at least I have some skills in sewing.
I will handle things myself.
Sorry to make things difficult for you.
Consort Estime to pay her respects!
Peace to Your Majesty.
Lady Sourire has already arrived at Penglai Island.
You may rise.
We can’t even see her off as sisters.
Noble Lady An is loyal, to the point of going with her.
Given Consort Fleur's current status,
it’s not a bad choice to get as far away as possible.
She can't harm what she can't see.
It’s actually us who suffer more, having to live with
Consort Fleur’s moods and attitudes.
Hearing Your Majesty's saying so
is unbearable to us concubines.
Everything in the harem
relies on Your Majesty's authority.
What can I do?
Consort Fleur already walks all over me as she pleases.
Not exactly.
Even though His Majesty spoils
Consort Fleur and Companion Zhi,
he is unequivocal with Nian Gengyao.
What does Your Highness have to worry about?
Your Majesty is the head of the Imperial Harem,
and we all obey your orders.
Consort Fleur cannot "perform an
opera as the only actor on stage."
I understand
and I'm fortunate to have you all here.
With Concubine Sourire and Lady An gone,
if we don’t remain united in one mind,
I’m afraid we will be next to be sent to Penglai Island.
We will only obey Your Majesty!
I know.
All rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
Zhou Ninghai bows in respect before Your Majesty.
Your Majesty,
Consort Fleur will accompany His Majesty during
breakfast and cannot pay her respects today.
She hopes Your Majesty understands.
What about Companion Zhi?
Companion Zhi is also serving His Majesty.
She is also unable to come.
I don’t think Your Majesty will mind
absence from such trivial matters
as paying daily respects.
If paying respects is trivial, then what is important?
It's all right, Attendant Joie.
His Majesty’s affairs are the most important.
Zhou Ninghai, you may leave now.
Allow me to take my leave, Your Majesty.
Autumn is coming.
His Majesty is coming back soon, right?
Yes, I heard that His Majesty is
coming back early next month.
So Consort Estime will be back soon too?
Yes, Her Highness is coming back soon.
However, Concubine Sourire won’t be returning.
What did you say?
I didn’t dare tell you, My Lady.
Lady Sourire enraged His Majesty,
and was banished to Penglai Island.
Penglai Island is even worse than the Cold Palace.
It’s more like a jail.
That’s right.
I heard that no one is cleaning the Palace of Pearl Jade
even though His Majesty is returning soon.
I'm afraid that Lady Sourire won’t be
coming back this time.
Lady Sourire is there by herself, without anything.
How pitiful!
I wonder how she is managing.
My Lady, perhaps we could have
someone send some supplies over?
She used to be favored by His Majesty so much.
Why would she need anything that we have?
Were you thinking of His Majesty, Sourire?
No, nothing particular,
just thinking about myself.
I’m afraid His Majesty has forgotten all about us.
How could we know whether he has or not?
Don’t be so upset.
The carp tofu soup I am making is almost ready.
Let’s go eat.
You go ahead first, I’ll join you in a bit.
Quickly.
- Mr. Su.
- Peace to Your Highness.
Your Highness, it is becoming autumn.
Your Highness did not bring any fall clothing with you.
So Lady Vertu sent over some clothes and sundries.
I appreciate that Meizhuang is still thinking about me.
That’s Noble Lady Vertu.
Her words may be harsh but her heart is kind.
She told us it was meant for Lady An,
but everything came in pairs.
She hasn’t forgotten about Your Highness.
How is Your Highness?
His Majesty worries a lot about you.
I am very well, please convey that to His Majesty.
Yes.
- And how is His Majesty?
- He is well!
And is everything going well?
Indeed they are, Your Highness.
Please rest easy.
That’s good.
Your Highness, I came here to inform you that
His Majesty is returning to the palace tomorrow.
We don’t know about the situation in the capital.
Please take good care of His Majesty.
I will.
I am also leaving tomorrow.
This is my apprentice, Xiao-Xiazi.
He is pretty clever.
He will be in charge of sending things to
Your Highness in the future.
Heaven forbid, but if anything goes wrong in the capital,
you must send someone to inform me.
His Majesty's greatest fear is that
Your Highness would be harmed,
which is why he sent you here for the time being.
My only wish is for His Majesty to be safe and well.
He will be. I can’t stay for too long.
Allow me to take my leave.
Yes.
- You are back.
- Your Majesty.
I came urgently because
I intercepted this message.
It's from a carrier pigeon that left
State Prince Dun’s residence.
As I expected, State Prince Dun is
asking Nian Gengyao for assistance
in usurping my throne.
They will make Yunsi [Lord VIII] the emperor,
and Yuntang's [Lord IX] mother
Consort Dowager Bonheur the Empress Dowager.
Given that this is State Prince Dun,
there is no chance he will succeed.
If he is successful, Heaven must not favor the Great Qing.
Xia Yi!
Your Majesty.
Tell your people in the Flying Guillotine
to secretly surveil State Prince Dun’s estate.
I will send the Valiant Cavalry there
and have everyone arrested tonight!
Yes.
I appreciate your effort.
I am only doing what little I’m capable of.
You are the only person who can visit State Prince
Dun’s residence without causing suspicion.
The evidence fully justifies the deployment of forces.
Keep watch over State Prince Dun’s
residence for me tonight.
Come to me immediately if anything goes wrong.
Yes.
Su Peisheng.
Your Majesty.
Announce this to the Empress Dowager:
“The Empress Dowager doesn’t feel well.
State Prince Dun’s wife and son
are summoned to serve Her Majesty,
together with Noble Princess Gongding
[Dun’s daughter who lives in the palace].”
As Your Majesty commands.
Her Majesty has also given me the order.
It has been almost a month since
His Majesty returned to the palace.
It’s already become autumn so soon.
What’s wrong?
My hands got tired from holding the book.
[The Xuanwu Gate Incident]
No wonder you are scared, this is about the
Xuanwu Gate Incident [a palace coup in Tang Dynasty].
I lost the courage to read it.
In wars between brothers, you win or you die.
“The winner will be enthroned, and the losers outlawed.”
Life or death, glory or disgrace.
That is all they come to.
That is the province of men.
For us women, life or death,
glory or disgrace, nobility or ordinary,
are all granted by His Majesty.
When His majesty enjoys glory, we might or might not,
but when His Majesty suffers disgrace, we suffer along.
Can you not let go of thoughts of His Majesty?
It’s not that I can't let go.
But after all these years,
I realize I've had more to care about
aside from my life and my family.
And ultimately, for my whole life,
this is who I'm married to.
Indeed.
Your mind seems ill at ease lately-
is there something troubling you?
"Good news follows when a candle sparks."
Whatever’s bothering you
will go away.
Look at Vermilion,
she becomes much sleepier when the weather turns cold.
I roasted some taro in the brazier.
Eat them while they are warm.
Taros!
I haven’t had these in a long time.
We ate them all the time at home.
They smell delicious!
Help yourself.
Your Majesty.
How did it go?
Everything went well.
The Valiant Cavalry has detained State Prince Dun.
When the prior emperor was still alive,
Yunsi, Yuntang, and Yun-e colluded in a heinous act,
aiming to revolt against the throne.
Yunsi and Yuntang went too far and they failed.
Their noble titles were removed.
Yun-e merely followed
and was spared for the sake of Noble Consort Wenxi.
To appease him,
I even granted him the title of State Prince,
but he is much too greedy!
I agree.
You have worked hard tonight.
It is unfortunate you have to witness
brothers turning against each other.
It must be hard on you.
However, there are many more powerful
members in the imperial clan,
I hope Yun-e is the last to harbor rebellious intentions
and that all the lords will stay within
the bounds of duty from now on.
I can’t speak for others,
but my interests are "wind, snow, flowers, and the moon."
I hope Your Majesty's prosperity persists
so you won't
assign me any more heart-wrenching matters.
Since you have said so,
I will do you that favor.
I thank Your Majesty.
Has Companion An woken up yet?
She stayed up late doing needlework.
My Lady, look!
What are you doing?
His Majesty told me
nothing is completely certain.
If something unforeseen happens,
I should defend myself.
But I have promised his Majesty,
if the evil defeats the good,
I will not live on in shame.
My Lady!
If his Majesty is defeated,
I won't be able to rescue myself.
Rather than being humiliated and tortured,
I would end my life.
Xiao-Xiazi!
Is His Majesty safe?
His Majesty is safe and well, Your Highness.
It succeeded!
Your Highness.
Don’t cry, Your Highness.
It’s a joyous time.
His Majesty sends me to welcome Your Highness
and Lady An back to the palace.
Hurry and prepare!
We were parted for two months
and you have slimmed down.
Penglai Island is very isolated.
I lost sleep worrying about you, Si Lang.
I did too.
That's why I have come to see you immediately.
Lady An is truly bonded with you.
When she heard you were
to be confined on Penglai Island,
she came to me in tears
begging to go with you.
Sharing weals is easy, sharing woes is rare.
"Charcoal sent on a snowy day" warms the heart.
Lingrong is as faithful as your Majesty says,
but I dare not tell her the truth.
It’s better for one less person to know.
Is your Majesty well?
Since your return,
you have asked me that quite a few times.
Really …
I did not notice.
No matter,
everything is over now.
It’s all over?
State Prince Dun and Yun-e are
imprisoned in the Imperial Clan Court.
Yunsi has been renamed Akina;
Yun Tang is renamed Seche.
Akina, Seche?
They mean "dog" and "pig" in Manchu.
These men committed treason.
Naming them "Pig" and "Dog"
insults actual pigs and dogs.
Your Majesty took down State Prince Dun swiftly.
It’s a blessing from Heaven
that everything went smoothly.
I want to tell you one more thing.
Before State Prince Dun acted on his ill intention,
he had planned to borrow forces from Nian Gengyao.
A secret letter was intercepted by Noble Prince Guo.
If Nian Gengyao had received that message,
what would he have done?
I am not sure.
I believe ...
he won’t really dare to rebel
for the sake of his current wealth and honor.
If he were to take the risk,
he would not obtain more
than what he already possesses.
Nian Gengyao has already spoken
words of resentment against me.
But his actions would be impeded
by his concern for Consort Fleur.
But I wonder
why State Prince Dun contacted
Nian Gengyao in particular,
and not others?
I will give it some thought.
I don’t care about the others.
I only know, in order to put on this act with me,
you have been through enough.
In fact,
I did not have to exile you to Penglai Island.
I was just afraid that if anything went amiss,
you would be hurt.
Besides,
your absence
lowered Nian Gengyao and Consort Nian’s vigilance.
I understand.
For the welfare of the state and Your Majesty,
such hardship does not matter to me.
Huan Huan, you truly understand me.
Peace and grace to Your Majesty.
Come early tomorrow if you wish to pay your respects.
You have just returned.
Coming at such a late hour, aren’t you tired?
I am full of gratitude towards your Majesty.
If I didn’t come to greet your Majesty tonight,
I would feel ill at ease.
You may rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
You did not complain of anything to
Concubine Sourire on your way back, did you?
No, I did not. I kept to my place
and spoke only when necessary.
Very well.
Concubine Sourire could not tell you
what His Majesty had ordered
If you had complained and
your words had reached His Majesty,
he would have seen you as an insensible person,
but praised her devotion to
keeping confidential information.
If you are acquiescent,
His Majesty will think highly of you.
His Majesty had high praise
for your righteous act to accompany Concubine Sourire.
I originally hesitated.
Without Your Majesty's enlightenment,
I would have gone with reservations.
Concubine Sourire is too intelligent.
You must show your relative dullness
to accentuate her intelligence.
Although I don’t fully understand,
I will always obey Your Majesty.
His Majesty now speaks to me less
and less about his concerns.
I have to stay informed,
or else Concubine Sourire will always be a step ahead
and she might become the second Consort Fleur.
I doubt if Zhen Huan will be.
She is not capable of that.
His Majesty's favor demonstrates her capabilities.
But her mind is unknown.
It’s better to err on the side of caution.
I learned a lot from Your Majesty.
State Prince Dun’s downfall
was a blow to Nian Gengyao as well.
And Consort Fleur ...
Your Majesty can at least put your mind at ease for now.
Can I?
It’s still too early.
Peace and grace to Your Majesty
You may rise.
I thank Your Majesty
I am not feeling well. I will take my leave now.
That is fine. There is nothing urgent today.
You may all go back to your palaces.
Concubine Sourire, you will stay.
I bid Your Majesty goodbye.
Please sit.
I thank Your Majesty.
You’ve endured much.
Your Majesty has endured more
serving alongside His Majesty.
I thank Your Majesty.
You and I both share His Majesty’s burdens.
We need to give our utmost.
Consort Fleur may not keep her status
under the current circumstances.
Those close to her may be affected as well.
Disregarding the dead and the deranged,
there are not many concubines left in the harem.
Does Your Majesty intend to hold
another round of selections?
His Majesty is unwilling.
But the Empress Dowager and I have observed that
many honorable officials contributed to suppressing
the rebellion of State Prince Dun.
From these meritorious families,
it would be desirable to select women
of the right age to enter into the harem.
Women from such respectable families
will be educated and well-mannered.
It seems that His Majesty, me, and you
are thinking along the same lines.
Then I will decide on a good date
to welcome them into the palace.
Your Majesty is the distinguished head of the harem.
We will obey Your Majesty's decision.
Speaking of family,
you are also from a meritorious family.
Your Majesty praises me too highly.
I dare not take any credit.
His Majesty and I are well aware
of the contribution you have made.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: The Lonely Phoenix
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
I dimly recall the colorful blooms in every summer.
They are as distant as the autumn moon in the water.
He loved me with a volatile heart.
And before I knew it, we fell apart.
Behind me are the promises and longing.
Before me lie the flute and the zither.
I loved you with my body and soul
But you hurt me from head to toe.
My wish ran athwart
and I ended up a fool of my destiny.
My love was the wind-swept flowers from a tree.
A plum bloomed in winter hoping for a fruitful summer.
But the irresistible winds of destiny destroyed her wish.
You can hear the flapping of a phoenix
but you will never see it.
What you see is the falling leaves from the phoenix tree.
The falling leaves from the phoenix tree.